iogear.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Statement - IOGEAR

[Effective Date: 09-25-2015]  
To review past versions of our Policy, email: [webmaster@iogear.com](mailto:webmaster@iogear.com)

## Privacy Policy

IOGEAR respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this IOGEAR Privacy Policy ("Policy"). This Policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit our websites, including, IOGEAR.com, [SHOPIOGEAR.com](http://www.shopiogear.com/), [KALIBERGAMING.com](http://kalibergaming.com/) and other landing pages and websites hosted by IOGEAR ("Sites") or utilize or participate in other IOGEAR services ("Services"). By ensuring that you are aware of and understand this Policy, we can provide you with better service. Please take a moment to read the following Policy to learn how we handle your Personal Information.

### Information We Collect

In describing our collection, use, and sharing of information in this Policy, we refer to our collection and use of "Personal Information." "Personal Information," as used in this Policy, is personally identifiable information, which is information that directly identifies an individual, such as first and last name, mailing address, email address, company name, billing information, IP addresses, demographics, passwords or other online contact information, or telephone number. We collect Personal Information, as well as non-personally identifiable information on IOGEAR Sites and/or Services.

We collect Personal Information in two ways. First, we collect information you provide to us in optional, voluntary submissions, such as in registration forms, user profiles, promotional signups, sweepstakes/contest entries, online surveys, requests for customer service, software and mobile applications downloads and curriculum vitae submissions. Second, some Personal Information may be collected automatically. This is described below in "Passive Data Collection."

We may also obtain information, including Personal Information, from third party sources. If we directly combine information from third parties with Personal Information that we have collected, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information and handle it in accordance with this Policy. In addition, please note that we may solicit third parties to collect Personal Information on our behalf and in such cases we instruct those third parties to comply with this Policy and all applicable data protection laws.

### Passive Data Collection

We may receive passively-collected information through a variety of methods including, but not limited to: several different types of cookies, location based services, analytics tools, web beacons, and other tracking technologies.

### a. Cookies

We may use a variety of methods, including "cookies" to collect information.

### What is a cookie?

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognize a user's device. You can find more information about cookies at: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improve the user experience. They can also help to ensure that advertisements you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.

### Performance Cookies

IOGEAR collects cookies on our Sites and/or Services to capture information about page visits (e.g. "performance cookies"). This information is anonymous and IOGEAR uses this information only internally - to deliver the most effective content to our visitors. Information from the cookie is used to gauge page popularity, analyze traffic patterns on our Sites and/or Services and guide development of other improvements to our Sites and/or Services.

### Targeting, Performance, and Functionality Cookies

In our email programs, IOGEAR employs some tracking methods (e.g. "targeting, performance, and functionality cookies"). We track "opens" via a tracking pixel in the email- meaning, we track who opens our e-mail messages and when you open our e-mail messages; and we track "clicks" via encoded URLs-meaning, we track whether you click on the links contained in our e-mail messages. This information is used internally only to help us deliver relevant messaging, and is not shared with any third parties, outside of the business purposes described in this Policy.

### Functionality and Necessary Cookies

IOGEAR does not require that you accept cookies and/or you may withdraw your consent to our use of cookies at any time by adjusting your browser's privacy settings,; however, some functionality on our Sites (e.g. "functionality cookies"), our product or service check-out process, and Services may be disabled if you decline to accept cookies ( e.g. "necessary cookies").

### Flash Cookies

Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Sites. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. 

### Opting Out of Cookies

Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited. 

### b. Location-Based Services

We may collect, use, and share (with IOGEAR business units, partners, and service providers) precise location data, including the real-time location of your mobile or fixed location device using services including, but not limited to: Google Analytics and Act-On.

You may opt out by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page. For more information, please visit: <http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>

For more information about opting out of Act-On services, please visit: <https://www.act-on.com/privacy-policy/>

### c. Analytics Tools

We use analytics tools and other third party technologies, including, but not limited to Google Analytics, Google Marketing Beacons, Act-On, Act-On Beacon, Easy2, Webcollage, and DoubleClick Cookies, to collect non-personal information in the form of various usage and user metrics when you use our online Sites and/or Services. These tools and technologies collect and analyze certain types of information, including cookies, IP addresses, device and software identifiers, referring and exit URLs, onsite behavior and usage information, feature use metrics and statistics, usage and purchase history, MAC Address, mobile unique device ID, and other similar information.

The third party analytics companies who collect information on our Sites and/or Services and other online products and/or services may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other websites and/or other online or mobile products and services relating to your activities across their network of websites as well as online and/or mobile products and services. Many of these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies.

In addition to our use of technologies as described herein, we may permit certain third party companies to help us tailor advertising that we think may be of interest to you based on your use of IOGEAR Sites and/or services and to otherwise collect and use data about your use of IOGEAR Sites and/or Services. For more information about this practice, please see the "Third Party Advertising Technologies" section below.

For information on opting out of the above third party technologies:  
DoubleClick Cookies: visit the Google Advertising opt-out page  
Google Analytics: visit the Google Analytics opt-out page, <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
Google Remarketing Privacy Guidelines: visit <http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>  
Act-On: visit <https://www.act-on.com/privacy-policy/>  
Easy2: visit <http://www.easy2.com/resources/privacy-policy.html>  
Webcollage: visit <https://www.webcollage.net/MainApp/privacy/privacy-policy>

### 2\. How We Use Information

Generally, we use Personal Information to establish and enhance our relationship with our users through four main categories: (1) Communication; (2) Optimization; (3) Advertising; and (4) Sharing Features. Below, we provide some specific examples of how we use the Personal Information and other information we collect.

### Communication and Responding to Requests

We use your information, including Personal Information to provide you with customer support, process transactions, respond to users' requests, send newsletters and updates, send special offers and advertisements, seek your opinions and feedback, to connect users to IOGEAR Sites and/or Services, and to products and services of our partners and licensees, and other similar communications and activities.

### Optimization

We use user information, including Personal Information, behavioral metrics, and other non-personally identifiable information to operate, provide, improve, and maintain our Sites and Services, to develop new products and services, to prevent abuse and fraud, to personalize and display advertisements and other content for you, and for other administrative and internal business purposes.

### Advertising

We use user information, including Personal Information, behavioral metrics, geo-location data, demographic data and marketing preferences to personalize and display advertisements and other content for you.

### 3\. When We Disclose Personal Information

We do not share Personal Information with third parties except in the limited circumstances described in this Policy.

### IOGEAR/ATEN Group

IOGEAR is part of a global company, ATEN International, Co., Ltd. ("ATEN"); therefore your Personal Information may be shared with IOGEAR or ATEN corporate offices in different countries, for business purposes only. They will protect your Personal Information in accordance with the Policy.

### Service Providers

We may provide Personal Information to third parties for their use in performing internal business functions (e.g., payment processing, customer service, shipping, maintenance, security, data analysis, email transmission, beta testing, or data hosting) on our behalf. Additionally, some third party service providers may collect information, including Personal Information, on our behalf. Whenever possible, we require such third-parties to only collect and use Personal Information in accordance with this Policy, to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of such Personal Information, and for no purpose other than providing us with our requested services.

### Legal Requirements

We may disclose Personal Information if we have a good-faith belief that doing so is required by a subpoena, warrant, or other judicial or administrative order or otherwise required by law. Additionally, we may disclose Personal Information where we, in good faith, deem it appropriate or necessary to prevent violation of our Terms of Use or End User License Agreements, or our other agreements; take precautions against liability; protect our rights, property, or safety, or those of a partner, any individual or the general public; maintain and protect the security and integrity of our Sites and/or Services or infrastructure; protect ourselves and our Sites and/or Services from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; investigate and defend ourselves against third party claims or allegations; or assist government regulatory agencies.

### IOGEAR reserves the right to transfer user information in connection with a sale of the business or its assets, including sales in bankruptcy proceedings or liquidation where the business is not continuing as a going concern.

### 4\. Third Party Advertising Technologies

In addition to using cookies and related technologies as described above, we also may permit certain third party companies to help us tailor advertising that we think may be of interest to users and to collect and use other data about user activities on our Sites and/or Services (e.g., to allow them to tailor ads on third party services). These companies may deliver ads that might also place cookies and otherwise track user behavior. These companies may use information about user behavior in order to provide customized advertisements across various services and products. In the course of providing these services, products or placing advertisements, these third party companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your computer, and may record information to these cookies based upon your activities on any of our Sites and/or Services and on third party websites. Each of these companies uses this cookie information according to their own privacy and security policies. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out as indicated in this Policy. Please note this does not opt you out of being delivered advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### 5\. Your Choices

If you choose to provide Personal Information about yourself, IOGEAR will use this information only to communicate directly with you. IOGEAR will not sell, rent or otherwise disclose that information to third parties unless such disclosure is necessary for the purposes set forth in this Policy, by law or a policy or notice contained or associated with a specific Site(s) and/or Service(s).

### Submitting Personal Information

If you do not want to submit Personal Information that is necessary to provide or use our Sites and/or Services or to fulfill your request, you will not be able to access and/or participate in certain IOGEAR Sites and/or Services. For example, you will not be able to register for an account with us or participate in certain contests or promotions, or access and/or use certain IOGEAR product features or online services. In addition, your refusal to submit Personal Information may limit our ability to respond to your customer support inquiry in a timely fashion.

### Editing Personal Information

You may, at any time, update, correct, or delete certain Personal Information that you have provided to us by contacting us at [support@iogear.com](mailto:support@iogear.com) and [webmaster@iogear.com](mailto:webmaster@iogear.com).

### Marketing Choices

If you want to remove yourself from individual communications, including marketing promotions, advertisements, updates and email newsletters, simply click the unsubscribe link in the communication or visit: <http://www.iogear.com/press/newsflash/subscription/>. You also acknowledge and agree that there may be instances where we may elect to notify you about administrative notices regarding your account with us, such as to inform you about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies, that your account may be expiring, or to provide you with other relevant administrative information about your account. Because this information is important to your interaction with us, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.

### Account Deletion

If you submit Personal Information, you may delete your account with us at any time. If you delete your account, your Personal Information and any and all other account related information including, but not limited to, user profile data, purchasing history, sharing data and any other data, credits, or content specifically associated with your account are also permanently deleted. Deletion of your data may take up to 30 days from accessible systems and up to 90 days from backup systems. If you choose to have an account with us in the future, you will have to sign up for a new account as none of the information you previously provided or saved within your account will have been saved.

### 6\. Security

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

IOGEAR utilizes the services of Digital River, Inc. for its ecommerce solutions. Any credit card or other information you provide for purposes of a purchase through the IOGEAR Store will be subject to Digital River's security standards and privacy policy: <https://www.shopiogear.com/store/defaults/en_US/DisplayDRPrivacyPolicyPage/eCommerceProvider>.

Please be aware that no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on our Sites.

If we learn of a security systems breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using the IOGEAR Sites and/or Services covered by this Policy and providing Personal Information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your account information and usage.

### 7\. Data Integrity and Data Retention

We collect and use Personal Information in accordance with this Policy and only for the purposes stated in this Policy and/or at the time we request such Personal Information from our users, or for such purposes to which a user may otherwise consent. We do not use or share our users' Personal Information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which such Personal Information was requested and authorized for use by us. We retain Personal Information for no longer than is commercially useful to carry out our business purposes, or as we believe may be legally required. When Personal Information is deleted or updated by you, it may take up to 30 days from accessible systems, and up to 90 days from backup systems, for us to delete such Personal Information.

### 8\. Access to Personal Information

You may view, correct, or delete the Personal Information IOGEAR stores about you. If you wish to obtain a report of the Personal Information IOGEAR has about you, please send us a written request at [support@iogear.com](mailto:support@iogear.com) and [webmaster@iogear.com](mailto:webmaster@iogear.com)

### 10\. Third Party Services and Links

### Third Party Services

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located in a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your Personal Information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store's website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Policy or the Terms of our Sites and Services.

### Links

IOGEAR's content, products, services, newsletters and communications that we send to our users, may contain links to content provided by third-parties and may direct you away from our site. For example, our content may contain links to third party merchants ( i.e. Amazon.com) from whom you may purchase products. To purchase products from these third party merchants, you may be required to provide Personal Information, including your credit card or other payment information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of thrid party sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

### 11\. California Privacy Rights

In addition to the rights set forth in this Policy, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who are individual consumers or users of IOGEAR Sites and/or Services, or services to request certain information regarding its disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us via mail or email at [support@iogear.com](mailto:support@iogear.com) and [webmaster@iogear.com](mailto:webmaster@iogear.com).

### 12\. Age of Consent

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this Site.

### Children Under the Age of 13

Our Sites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any Personal Information to the Sites. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on the Sites, register on the Sites, make any purchases through the Sites, use any of the interactive or public comment features of the Sites or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received Personal Information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [support@iogear.com](mailto:support@iogear.com) and [webmaster@iogear.com](mailto:webmaster@iogear.com).

### 13\. Changes and Updates to This Policy

We may update this Policy from time to time. If we do, we will update the "effective date" at the top of the Policy. If we make material changes to how we use Personal Information, we will attempt to notify you of the change and to give you the opportunity to exercise choice as to how your Personal Information is used. We will post the updated Policy on the affected Sites and/or Service, and if we have your email address, we will send notice of the update to that email address.

We encourage you to review this Policy periodically to stay informed about our collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information. Your continued use of our Sites and/or Services or any other content, products or other services covered by this Policy constitutes your agreement to this Policy and any updates.

### 14\. Enforcement

IOGEAR regularly reviews its compliance with this Privacy Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy or IOGEAR's treatment of Personal Information by contacting us at [support@iogear.com](mailto:support@iogear.com) and [webmaster@iogear.com](mailto:webmaster@iogear.com). When IOGEAR receives a complaint at this email address, it is IOGEAR's policy to contact the complaining party regarding his or her concerns. IOGEAR will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved by IOGEAR and an individual.

### 15\. No Error Free Performance

IOGEAR does not guarantee error-free performance under this Privacy Policy. IOGEAR will use reasonable efforts to comply with this Privacy Policy and will take prompt corrective action when IOGEAR learns of any failure to comply with our Privacy Policy. IOGEAR shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of California and the United States, to the extent applicable.
